Tua, welcome to Atlanta home team
Brandon leak from sports radio 680 the
fan. Uh two-parter uh the competitor in
you do you uh expect to be the starting
quarterback this year? And then the
second part is what made Atlanta the
right move for you with other
opportunities available to you uh this
free reagent market?
>> Yeah, that's a good question. Uh to
answer the first one, I would say you
don't you don't choose a team based off
of whether I'm going to be starting or
not. I think you look at the entirety of
of the group, right? Um as I was looking
at the other teams,
you know, I I knew I had to compete
regardless of what what that was going
to look like. uh coming here, you know,
I I kind of know Mike a little bit based
off of um his relationship with my
little brother as they were coming out
uh for the draft. So, in that sense, you
know, I I kind of got in contact with
Mike and whatnot. Uh talked with him and
uh moving forward from from there,
competition is just a thing in the NFL.
Uh I am no stranger to competition. had
it in college. Uh, and I would say
competition is just going to be there
and competition enhances uh the play of
everyone that you're surrounded with.
And so, you know, last year wasn't the
best year for me. And, you know, I'm
looking for a a fresh start, but fresh
start in the sense of being able to
compete, being able to go back out there
and playing football, good football. And
I think the best football is still ahead
of me.
All right, we'll go to Josh Kendall.
>> Hey. Hey to a Josh Kendall with the
Athletic. Nice to meet you. You've
mentioned a couple of times I feel like
looking for a fresh start, looking to
for a bounce back. Maybe that's not
exactly your words. What happened from
your diagnosis last year um that you
want to bounce back from or last two
years maybe?
If you're looking at last year, uh, my
play wasn't up to the standard of the
way I've been playing football
the past what, three years since, um,
since the new contract. So,
just got to play better football. That
that's that's what that that really
means. There's no
other way to sugarcoat that or go around
that.
Okay, Daniel Flick from AJC.
>> Yeah, I guess kind of on that note to
it, just how much of a drive do you feel
to kind of prove that you still have it
in you after the way the last few years
have been for you?
Yeah, I would say more so last year has
been been the biggest um
you know setback that I felt wasn't up
to par of what um the standard of play
should have been. Um injuries happen,
you know, those those are things that we
can't control as football players, but
outside of that, the drive the drive is
there. Um, you know, I just think of the
the 12-year-old self, the 14year-old
self, 13-year-old self. What would that
Tua say to the Tua now? I mean, it's a
blessing for me to be in this position
and this opportunity that I I have to be
able to play for, you know, the Falcons
and whatnot, but to be able to still
live out my dream, that's that's not
something that I take for granted. Um,
you know, so yeah, that's what I would
say.
>> All right, Allison from WSB.
>> Hey, Tua.
When we talk about, you know,
quarterbacks coming in, you are
considered now the most veteran
quarterback uh in this room right now.
So, I wanted to know kind of how do you
see that? Do you see yourself kind of as
a mentor coming in but or because you
are competing for that starting role?
It's just all business. I mean, how can
you maybe even help Michael?
>> Well, I look at myself when I was a
rookie. Um, and I was very grateful for
the chance that I had with someone like
Ryan Fitzpatrick. Um, and for me, I
think this is going to be the this is
actually going to be my second year
being what you would deem veteran of the
room. Last year was actually my first
year being the Otis in the room. Um,
with Quinn and Zach. So, this being my
second year, I think whatever I can do
to help Mike's game will help me because
if I'm helping getting him better, it's
helping me get better. vice versa within
helping the team get better. So, I'm not
looking at at at it as just, okay, you
do your thing. I'm a competitor. I'm
going to compete over here.
Everyone has to pull their own weight
with this. And it's it's the collection
of what what's best for the team, not
just the individual. So, I'm going to do
all that I can to help him and whatever
he needs with his game. And uh you know
by doing that I hope it enhances his
game to enhance mine and vice versa and
we keep growing and and battling
together in that sense.
>> Go to Jay Busby.
>> Hey to a Jay Busby from Yahoo. You
mentioned the difficulties last season.
What did you specifically learn from
those and what are you going to use how
are you going to use that to build on
for this coming season and the rest of
your career?
Yeah, I I've talked to a couple
veteran quarterbacks, you know, about
basically the season that I've had and,
you know, they've shared some of their
uh experiences of having tough seasons
and not having, you know,
I guess fun throughout those times, but
what they've learned and I've shared
what I've learned with them as well. And
we've come to common ground with things
that we've shared. Now I don't want to
share it but um you know I I I think if
if you don't have mentors and people
that you can um you know people that
have gone through through situations
like that that you can share and and
learn from. I think it makes it that
much more difficult to grow from it as
well. Um so I've learned a lot. I've
definitely learned a lot uh not just on
the field but also off the field. um you
know, in my preparation and and in
things of that nature. But
I think it's all for the good. It's all
it's all to to help you grow as a
person, be the best version of yourself.
And I think I think that's what I got
out of that.
>> Anything specific that you can share?
Not trade secrets or anything, but uh
anything specific?
>> Yeah, there's specific things probably
not to share. Uh, I think they're pretty
they're pretty uh
uh private. I I I think I would say so.
>> All right, we'll go to Maria Martin.
>> Hey T, two questions from me. Number
one, what do you think about this
offense that you're now joining? And
number two, what's it like for you to be
playing in a building that you've had a
lot of success in?
>> Yeah. one, I I got I got to spend some
time talking with Tommy, got to spend
some time talking with Kevin about the
offense. Um, you know, they they've
shared some things that it won't be as
adamant with the way we would motion in
Miami and and use, you know, our our
speeders in that sense, but uh there's
going to be a reason for for everything
that we do. Um, and then outside of
that, yeah, playing at Mercedes, it's it
it's it's good. It's it's fun and great
memories, you know, uh, playing at
Alabama and then being able to play the
Falcons last year. But I'm very excited
to play with these guys. Um, just
looking at last year, the way it went
for for them, you know, it's
heartbreaking, but you know, at the same
time, you got you got a new coaching
staff, you know, you you know, you got a
lot of the the guys that are the pillars
of the team that are there still. And
so, I'm excited to get to know more of
those guys, know more of the teammates,
know more of the coaches and whatnot on
a personal level.
>> Mark Randi, ESPN.
>> Hey, how are you, man? doing well, thank
you. How are you?
>> Pretty good. Pretty good. Uh, just
wanted to ask you, you know, you were
you were vocal at times last season
about things that were going on with the
team, uh, you know, with your teammates.
Uh, can you just give us some insight
into, you know, what it was like last
season in Miami and how that might have
shaped the season that you had?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I I don't want to
get too much in depth uh with things
that were going on uh more so in terms
of players to coaches than it was
players to players. Um, but it it was
unique in a sense. It was unique.
>> Unique in what way?
>> In a lot of ways.
We'll go to We'll go to Terrence more.
>> Terrence, can you hear us?
All right, we'll go to DJ. We'll we'll
come back to Terrence.
>> There you go.
>> Yeah. T, what up, man? Uh,
first off, man, welcome to the A, man.
Everybody excited to have you. Um
question I got for you. Obviously
playing the quarterback position uh
mentally is a big part of it. And you
spoke about some of the things you've
had to overcome good and bad. How have
you kind of blocked out some of the
stuff that's been said about you in the
past, but also motivated to be able to
move on and do better things and
continue to be the guy that you said you
want to be and compete now with this
fresh start. How do you get past it? Cuz
as we know, we live in a world of uh
it's hard to get away from social media
and all the things that people are
saying. And how do you balance all that
and still become the guy that you want
to be?
>> Yeah, it's that's a great question. I
don't have social media, so I don't see
any of any of that. Um, we have our our
team posting for us, like doing what the
the posts on Twitter, um, Instagram. I
don't know what else what else there
there is outside of that. Um, but yeah,
I would say that's that's been the
easiest way for me to block out the
noise. Now, my wife on the other hand,
my wife is totally different, right? I,
you know, I'm I'm with the kids. If
anything, social media for me um is
YouTube now. I like to fish. I like to
golf. I like to spearfish. So, you know,
I'll go watch those videos, see how guys
do. I enjoy boats. So, you know, I I
like looking at the Miami boat show. How
did they do? Uh the Fort Lauderdale boat
show, how, you know, what did that look
like? Things of that nature. So, uh I
keep myself busy. Um and I I would say
that makes it a lot easier for myself
not to get distracted by um what this
person is saying, what that person is
saying. Now, um the Ann Nolan for me is
Matt, right? So Matt would be the bearer
of bad news for me. Hey, just letting
you know as I'm preparing to tell you
what these guys are saying, like this is
what they're saying. I don't know how
you want to answer that. And you go from
there, right? So I would say that's how
I find out the news. Um, if it's not
like a family member calling me and
telling me, my wife already knows if if
it's not something good, you don't share
it with me unless unless it's that
important, right? So, yeah, I I would
say that's that's what's helped uh me. I
I don't have social media uh on my phone
outside of YouTube.
to one one last followup. Uh, is how
much has Matt been a Matt Ryan been a a
guy that you can lean on through this
process? I know obviously a guy who's
played in the league, who's been there,
done it, now he's a president of
football. How much uh have you leaned on
him so far to uh on your way to Atlanta
was that part of it as well?
>> Yeah, he's he he's been a big uh
influence in in the decision as well.
Um, you know, I've been talking a lot to
him about places to live, just the areas
and whatnot. Um,
so yeah, Matt Matt has had a big
influence and then we've talked um, you
know, outside of outside of that with
with football and you know, if I had any
questions
um, you know, his his his his room is
always open for me to go up there.
>> Go to Charles Odum.
>> Hi Tua. Uh, welcome to Atlanta. Uh, you
spoke of about the being attracted to
the entirety of the team. Can you
expound on that a little bit? And also,
do you think uh there's an advantage to
having uh two left-handed quarterbacks
in terms of maybe the comfort level for
the line and the the way the ball comes
out for the receivers?
>> Yeah, I I don't know if there's ever
been two lefties on the same same team.
I'm just trying to trying to think
through that. Um
I think that that's very unique in a
sense uh because of what I just said.
Uh, and I think it it makes it a lot
easier for the receivers. Um, you know,
in terms of the rotation of the ball
when you're throwing lefty and then
you're catching a righty ball. It, you
know, it it it is different. Now, the
receivers will tell you because they're
professionals, h it has no no effect on
me.
I think that's BS. It has an effect. It
has an effect. So, uh, yeah. Then
looking at the team, right? The guys,
you're looking at the defense.
Defense I think is solid. Okay, now
let's go to the offense. All right, you
got good line, you got Kyle Pittz, you
got Bejian Robinson, you got Drake
London, who Drake actually um Drake's
fiance, I'm really close with her dad.
Her dad has a spot out here. Yeah, I
know. It's the craziest thing. her dad
has a spot out here in Bakers Bay and
I don't know how I met him, but I met
him and then we ended up playing them
last year. Um, and I don't know, it was
the coolest thing foreshadowing to fast
forwarding uh that I'm, you know, here
with the Falcons. Uh, but yeah, you got
you got all these guys. You got a good
line and I'm excited to be able to use
those weapons in OTAAS and be able to
just work with these guys.
>> Try Terrence Moore again.
>> You there Terrence?
>> All right, we'll go we'll go back to
home team.
Tua uh when you look at the weapons as
you just spoke of uh here at Atlanta,
what stands out to you and how dangerous
do you think the offense can be if it
clicks? And do you also uh plan on
endearing yourself to the Atlanta
community going to Hawks games or going
to a Braves game?
>> I'm not opposed to to not going to any
of those games. Um you know, I want to
immerse myself in the community. I want
to be able to go out with the guys,
enjoy enjoy, you know, games, enjoy game
nights, whatever whatever that looks
like. Um, but I I think the biggest
thing you see with with the group of
guys that that we have, you got Yaking
Kyle Pittz, you can throw it in the
vicinity of Drake. Drake's going to
catch it. You got a back like Bejan. I
mean, we had Achan last year and you
could see the the similarities in in the
style of run. I think Bejian might be,
you know, a bit phys more physical. Um,
but in terms of speed, elusiveness,
then you got the play action game to
work off of that to get, you know, these
guys the ball. All in all, I I think it
can be really dangerous.
Josh Kendall,
>> hey to forgive me because I know that
this is old news for you, but can you
catch us up on where you are with your
health that the concussions, how
comfortable you are with that and moving
forward? I mean, obviously nobody has a
crystal ball on it.
>> Yeah, for sure. Um, the game of football
will always entail physicality, right?
So, you can never
foreshadow what what the future's going
to look like in terms of your health,
whether it's uh an ankle, whether it's a
hand injury, a concussion, um a hip
injury, what whatever that may be. In
terms of health,
went through all the protocols of what I
needed to do u for the Falcons.
Everything came out good. some things
are looking way better than than you
know the guys might have thought. So
you either love it or you don't. I I
that's what I would say. You either love
the game or you don't. Um and you know
what the challenges that you know you
know the challenges that are ahead uh in
terms of playing the sport with
injuries, but
you either love it or you don't. That's
what I would say. And if I can follow up
with one more that's sort of off off
that topic. Again, I know you don't have
a crystal ball, but do you approach this
as a professional saying this is the
start of something new or do you
approach this as saying I'm going to put
in a year. I'm going to get that reset.
This is a one-year contract. Then I'm
going to see where I am and what I feel
like doing. If that question makes
sense,
>> I think it makes sense.
I would say you Yeah, it it's hard to to
to look that far in front. Um I think
the best thing with right now is making
the best of this opportunity that I have
with the team on my one year and make
the best out of that in terms of the
relationships I make with these guys.
And then when I'm playing, I mean, I get
to freaking play football. This is what
I've dreamed of my entire life, you
know? So regardless of what that looks
like, um, it's got to I'm going to be
present. I'm going to be in the moment.
I'm going to be where my feet are. And
that's how I would say I' I'd answer
that. Thank you.
>> Got time for one more. We'll go Mark
Rami.
>> Hey, so kind of a similar question that
Josh just asked. I just want to ask you
about how much, you know, your mindset
has to change going from the Dolphins
where, you know, you were kind of, you
know, the guy the last few years, big
contract to now you're on a one-year
deal. It's going to be a competition
with Penn. How much does the mindset
have to change, if any?
>> I don't think the mindset changes at
all. Doesn't change. You either love
competition, you're either competitor or
you're not. It you just don't go from
being a competitor to ah, let me just
relax a little bit. I just don't think
that's how it works. You're either a
competitor or you're not. And so I
embrace the competition. I'm excited to
work alongside with Mike and I'm excited
to work, you know, with the team, with
the guys. I think it's going to be fun
this year.
>> All right. Thank you everybody.